<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on STOR-i Blog</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on STOR-i Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Changepoints &amp; Sensor Data</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-02-05-changepoints--sensor-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-02-05-changepoints--sensor-data/</guid>
      <description>Last week I attended a talk given by Professor Idris Eckley named &amp;ldquo;Making Sense of Sensor Data&amp;rdquo;. One of the main areas I see sensors being used everyday is my phone telling me how much I&amp;rsquo;ve walked. There is quite a few problems in sensor data. I&amp;rsquo;ll look at two of them here namely the changepoints in the data and the frequency at which we observe data
Changepoints The first is quite simple, suppose we observe a long uni-variate time series of some movement measure in a sensor call it n.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An &#34;Extreme&#34;ly interesting way to view data</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-01-26-an-extremely-interesting-way-to-view-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-01-26-an-extremely-interesting-way-to-view-data/</guid>
      <description>If you can&#39;t guess from the title this post is about Extreme Value Theory (EVT). Last week I attended a talk from Professor Jonathan Tawn on some EVT applications and Jenny Wadsworth on some theory in multivariate EVT. I found it particularly interesting as unlike most methods of analyzing data we don&#39;t really care about the data which isn&#39;t surprising, instead we focus on modelling the tail ends and unlikely observations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s Going on here?</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-12-12-whats-going-on-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-12-12-whats-going-on-here/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my Blog! I am an MRes student at STOR-i, Lancaster University and as part of my development as a student I will be maintaining a blog. STOR-i is a EPRSC funded Centre for Doctoral Training (CDT), it mainly focuses on applications of STatistics and Operations Research in Industry. To read more about me you can click on the &amp;ldquo;back to website&amp;rdquo; button above.
Anyways about the actual blog. In the MRes year at STOR-i we attend talks &amp;amp; master classes on quite a large variety of subjects in Statistics &amp;amp; Operations research, I will be writing blog posts about a selection of these which I find most interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>