<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on STOR-i Blog</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on STOR-i Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>An &#34;Extreme&#34;ly interesting way to view data</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-01-26-an-extremely-interesting-way-to-view-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-01-26-an-extremely-interesting-way-to-view-data/</guid>
      <description>If you can&#39;t guess from the title this post is about Extreme Value Theory (EVT). Last week I attended a talk from Professor Jonathan Tawn on some EVT applications and Jenny Wadsworth on some theory in multivariate EVT. I found it particularly interesting as unlike most methods of analyzing data we don&#39;t really care about the data which isn&#39;t surprising, instead we focus on modelling the tail ends and unlikely observations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s Going on here?</title>
      <link>/blog/2017-12-12-whats-going-on-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017-12-12-whats-going-on-here/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my Blog! I am an MRes student at STOR-i, Lancaster University and as part of my development as a student I will be maintaining a blog. STOR-i is a EPRSC funded Centre for Doctoral Training (CDT), it mainly focuses on applications of STatistics and Operations Research in Industry. To read more about me you can click on the &amp;ldquo;back to website&amp;rdquo; button above.
Anyways about the actual blog. In the MRes year at STOR-i we attend talks &amp;amp; master classes on quite a large variety of subjects in Statistics &amp;amp; Operations research, I will be writing blog posts about a selection of these which I find most interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>/blog/2015-07-23-hello-r-markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015-07-23-hello-r-markdown/</guid>
      <description>R MarkdownThis is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars)## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.98 ## 3rd Qu.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>